Who wants the
last dumpling?
만두 남은거 누가 먹을래?
Ooh, me!
나!
Penny, a moment.
페니, 잠깐만
We just had Thai food.
우린 태국음식을 먹었어
In that culture,
the last morsel is called
태국에서 마지막으로
남아있는 음식을
the "greng jie" piece,
and it is reserved for
'그랭 지에'라고 부르는데
the most important
and valued member of the group.
단체에서 가장 중요하고
힘이 센 멤버가 먹는거야
Thank you all
for this high honor.
그렇다면 내가 고맙게 먹을게
I've seen pictures
of your mother; keep eating.
어머니도 살이 찌셨던데
한 번 그렇게 계속 먹어봐
All right, honey, if we're gonna
make the movie, we should go.
자기, 영화보려면
이제 가야될것 같아
This may be hard
for you to hear,
너한테는 조금
힘들지 모르겠지만
but when I say "honey,"
I mean my fiancee.
내가 자기라고 한 건
내 약혼상대를 말한거야
Yeah, well, now it means her.
이제는 너 아니야
It's okay if he
wants to come.
같이 따라와도
난 상관없어
Fine. But next time,
we get a sitter.
좋아, 하지만 다음번엔
우리가 앉을데를 고를거야
All right, I got to go to work.
I'll walk down with you.
일하러 가 봐야겠다
너네랑 같이 갈게
Wait.
잠깐만
Which is closer to the new
train store in Monrovia,
시내에 새로 생긴
기차모형 가게가
the movie theater
or The Cheesecake Factory?
영화관이랑 가까워?
페니 일하는데랑 가까워?
Neither of them are close.
거긴 엄청 멀어
Oh, well, then I guess
it doesn't matter which one
그럼 너희중에 아무나
of you drives me.
날 태워주면 되겠네
Let's play a fun guessing game
그럼 우리 게임해서
to see who gets to take me.
이기는 사람이
날 태워가는걸로 하자
All right, this four-letter word
describes either
좋아, 네글자인데
a printer's type size
or a compulsion to eat dirt.
활자 크기의 단위나
흙을 먹고 싶은 충동을 뜻해
Okay, I'm not driving him.
난 얘 안데려갈거야
Penny, don't give up,
you can get this.
페니, 포기하지마
넌 할 수 있어
Aren't you going
with Sheldon?
셸든이랑 같이 안가?
No, I have no interest
in model trains,
아니, 나는 기차모형엔
별로 관심도 없고
stores that sell them, nor
their heartbreaking clientele.
그런 모형을 파는 상점이나
그런걸 사는 놈이나 관심없어
Oh.
Well, I have
some work to do, so...
I can't imagine
that would disturb me.
나는 괜찮으니까
Carry on.
어서 일 해
Okay.
알았어
Wouldn't you be
more comfortable at home?
집에 있는게 더 편하지 않아?
Not really, no.
아니 별로
All righty then.
알았어 그럼
Guess I'll just
get started.
그럼 일을 시작해야겠네
Leonard, please. I don't need
the running commentary.
레너드, 제발
일일이 설명하지 말아줘
♪ Our whole universe
was in a hot, dense state ♪
♪ Then nearly 14 billion years
ago expansion started... Wait! ♪
♪ The Earth began to cool ♪
♪ The autotrophs began to drool,
Neanderthals developed tools ♪
♪ We built the Wall ♪
♪ We built the pyramids ♪
♪ Math, Science, History,
unraveling the mystery ♪
♪ That all started
with a big bang ♪
♪ Bang! ♪
The Big Bang Theory 5x03
The Pulled Groin Extrapolation
Original Air Date on September 29, 2011
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
== translated by 김철영 doatip@gmail.com ==
(sighs softly)
- Amy?
- Yo.
You okay?
너 괜찮아?
Oh, sure.
괜찮아
I thought you were reading.
책 읽고 있는줄 알았는데
I was.
그랬지
Now I'm thinking about
what I read.
지금은 읽은 것에 대해
생각을 하고 있었어
You all right, Leonard?
너는 괜찮니 레너드?
You seem very uncomfortable.
매우 불편해보인다
I-I'm fine.
난 괜찮아
Should I go?
내가 집에 갈까?
I've been told sometimes
I overstay my welcome.
사람들이 내가 남의 집에
너무 오래 머무른다 하더라고
Wha... who told you that?
뭐... 누가 그래?
Well, most recently
my gynecologist.
음, 가장 최근에는
내 산부인과 의사가
Well, you stay
as long as you'd like.
너 편한만큼 여기 있어도 돼
I'm glad to hear you say that,
그렇게 말해줘서 고마워
because I'm having
a wonderful time.
즐거운 시간을 보내고 있거든
(chuckles)
I said the same thing
to my gynecologist.
What are you going to get
at the train store, Sheldon?
모형 기차 상점에서
뭘 살거야, 셸든?
Oh, I'm not
buying anything.
사러 가는거 아니야
They're having a lecture.
강좌를 열고 있거든
"H-O gauge railroading.
"HO 게이지 모형철도
Half the size of O-gauge,
but twice the fun."
O 게이지 철도보다
작지만 더 큰 즐거움"
Very controversial topic.
이거에 대해 말이 많더라
Which side do you come down on?
너는 어떤 게이지가 좋은데?
I'll let you know after tonight.
오늘밤이 지나면 알게될거야
Unlike some people,
I'm going in with an open mind.
다른 사람들과는 달리
나는 오픈마인드거든
Who am I kidding?
농담도 못하겠다
Of course we all know
it's O-gauge or no gauge.
O 게이지가 아니면
당연히 게이지가 아니지
Can you believe grown men sit
around and play with toy trains?
다 큰 사람들이 장난감을
가지고 노는게 웃기지?
That's pretty big talk
for a man
그러면서 정작 자기는
with a closet full of magic
tricks at his mother's house.
옷장에 마술 장난감이
한가득 있으면서
First of all, they're not
tricks, they're illusions.
일단, 한낱 장난감이 아닌
진지한 마술도구야
And...
그리고...
secondly, when we get
married, they're all going up
우리가 결혼하면
다락방에 다 옮길테니
in the attic so you can have
that closet for clothes.
옷장에는 옷만 넣으면 돼
Why would I keep clothes
at your mother's house?
어머니집에 우리 옷을
왜 보관하는데?
Well, don't think
of it that way.
어머니집이라니
Once we move in,
it'll be our house.
우리가 들어가면 우리집인데
Is she moving out?
어머니 나가신데?
Why would
she move out?
엄마가 어딜 나가?
It's her house.
엄마 집인데
Hang on.
잠깐만
You seriously think I'm going
to live with your mother?
내가 자기 어머니랑
같이 살거라고 생각해?
Howard, I think
I can help here.
하워드, 내가 도와줄게
Yes, Bernadette,
that's exactly what he thinks.
그래, 맞아
그게 쟤 생각이야
Why not?
왜 싫어?
It's a great house,
plenty of room,
좋은 집이라니까
방도 많잖아
and if we have kids,
Mom's there to help.
우리가 애를 낳으면
엄마가 길러주실거야
You know, en she tells "The
Three Little Pigs" story,
'새끼돼지 삼형제'이야기도
애들한테 들려주시겠지
she actually has hair
on her chinny-chin-chin.
털이 많으셔서
늑대흉내를 잘 내시거든
I'm not gonna live
with your mother.
난 어머니랑 같이 못살아
Not now, not ever.
지금이나 앞으로도
Wow, someone obviously
has some mommy issues.
너 어릴때 엄마랑
정말 안좋았나보네
Raj, take me home.
라지, 집으로 데려다줘
Don't listen to her.
Go to the movie theater.
쟤말 듣지마. 영화보러 가자
Take me home now.
집으로 데려다줘 당장!
Movie theater!
영화관!
(groans)
Okay, everybody
calm down.
There is a simple
solution here.
간단한 해결책이 있어
Raj, take me to the train store,
라지, 나를 모형상점에 데려다줘
and then I don't care
what you people do.
그리고 너네 일은
너네가 알아서 해
How was your shower?
샤워는 어땠어?
It was good, good.
좋아, 좋았지
Just out of curiosity, what time
do you usually go to bed?
궁금해서 그러는데
너 언제쯤 자냐?
Oh, I'm up all night.
난 잠을 안 자
I'm like a possum.
야생동물같지
Boy, you were not liked
in high school, were you?
너 고등학교때
인기 없었겠다, 맞지?
Not really.
아니야
- Is that my yearbook?
- Mm-hmm.
내 졸업사진이야?
"Dear Leonard,
you're really good at science.
"레너드에게
너 과학은 잘하더라
Maybe one day you'll come up
with a cure for being a dork."
열심히 해서 언젠가
멋있어지는 약을 개발좀 해"
Well, it wasn't spray-painting
a lightning bolt
그래도 어떤 애처럼
on my briefcase,
I can tell you that.
가방에 스프레이로
낙서를 당하지는 않았어
If it makes you feel any better,
너무 기분 상해있지마
the only person who signed
my yearbook was my mother.
내 졸업앨범에는
엄마만 싸인을 해줬거든
- Aw.
- "Dear Amy,
"에이미에게
"Self-respect and a hymen
are better than friends and fun.
"친구도 없고 재미가 없어도
네 자긍심과 순결함이 좋구나
Love, Mom."
사랑한다, 엄마가"
Well, you can add
Jerry's Junction
이제 제리의 기차역은
to the list of train stores
셸든 쿠퍼가 더 이상
Sheldon Cooper will never
set foot in again.
발을 붙일 모형 상점이
아니란것만 알아둬
Rough night, Casey Jones?
힘드셨어요, 역무원님?
You don't know
the half of it.
최악이었어
It was billed
광고에서는
as a lively give-and-take on
the merits of model train sizes.
모형의 사이즈에 대한
토론의 장이라고 했는데
But it was actually a setup
to intimidate
사실은 줏대없고 멍청한
시민들한테 물건을 파는
weak-minded spineless rubes
into buying H-O starter sets.
얄팍한 상술이었어
What's in the bag?
비닐봉투에 뭔데?
I don't want to talk about it.
이야기하고 싶지 않아
But it's not a spine,
I'll tell you that.
그냥 나도 줏대가
없었다고만 말해둘게
Well, I had a delightful
evening, Leonard.
재밌는 저녁이었어 레너드
We should do this
again sometime.
나중에 또 같이 놀자
Ah, sure.
That'd be nice.
아, 그래
그랬으면 좋겠다
Glad to hear it.
그렇다면 잘됐다
I need someone to accompany me
to the wedding
결혼식에 같이 갈
사람이 하나 필요하거든
of Dr. Moranelli
and Dr. Gustufson this Friday.
모라넬리 박사과 구스텁슨 박사가
이번주 금요일에 결혼을 한대
They're kind of
the Brad and Angelina
영장류 동물학계의
브랜젤리나 커플이라고
of the primatology department.
꽤 유명한 사람들이야
Wouldn't you rather
bring Sheldon?
셸든이랑 가지그래?
I would, but the last wedding
we went to was a disaster.
그러고 싶은데
정말 안좋은 경험이었어
He behaved like a child
the entire time.
결혼식에서 애처럼
행동을 하더라고
Not my fault.
내 잘못 아니다
You said there'd be
other scientists there my age.
내 또래의 과학자들이
있을거라고 했잖아
Doesn't matter.
You're out, he's in.
상관없어
넌 빠지고 얘랑 갈거야
No date to the prom,
two dates to a wedding.
졸업파티때는 아무도 없더니
결혼식에는 두 명이라
Hmm, how times change.
흠, 참 세월이란
(singsongy): Ha-ha, you have
to go to a wedding.
하하, 결혼가야 된대요~
(doorbell rings)
WOLOWITZ:
I'll get it!
MRS. WOLOWITZ:
Could you get it?!
네가 나가줄래?!
I just said
I'm getting it!
내가 나간다고
방금 그랬잖아!
Fine, I'll get it!
알았다, 내가 가마!
I got it!
벌써 왔어!
Oh, hi.
아, 안녕
Hey.
안녕
I don't want to fight.
싸우고 싶지 않아
I was just surprised
when you sprung
갑자기 예고도 없이
엄마랑 살자는 이야기를
the whole living-with-your-mom
stuff on me.
꺼내니까 내가 당황한거야
Yeah, well, I'm sorry I
didn't run it by you first.
그래, 먼저 얘기 안해서 미안해
MRS. WOLOWITZ: I don't know who
you're talking to,
누구랑 얘기하는거냐!
but in or out!
들어오던지 말던지!
We don't need bugs!
벌레들어오겠다!
The bugs
only come here
벌레가 들어오는 이유는
because you're
their queen!
엄마가 벌레여왕이라서 그래!
Listen, how about this.
잠깐, 이러면 어떨까
Before we make any
kind of decision
어디에서 같이 살까
이런걸 결정하기 전에
about where we live,
we have a trial run.
일단 체험을 해 보는거야
Stay here for a weekend,
see what it's like.
여기 주말동안 있으면서
괜찮을지 생각해봐
And your mom would be
okay with that?
어머니가 괜찮아 하실까?
Sure she would.
당연히 괜찮아 하시지
Ma, do you mind if Bernadette
stays here this weekend?!
엄마, 버나뎃이 주말동안
여기서 지내도 괜찮지?!
MRS. WOLOWITZ: Hey, if she's willing to
give the milk away for free,
공짜로 얹혀 살겠다는데
who am I to say no?!
정말 환영한다!
See? She's
good with it.
봤지? 괜찮아 하신다니까
MRS. WOLOWITZ: Frankly, after all
your sleepovers
솔직히 말해서
인도놈이랑 자는거보다
with the little brown boy,
a girl is a big relief!
여자랑 잔다니까 마음이 놓인다!
All these years,
I've been so wrong.
너희를 너무 과소평가했다
The tinier the train,
the more concentrated the fun.
기차가 작을수록
재미가 더 응집되어있어
You're a brain scientist.
너 사람뇌 전문가라며
Can you explain to me
why a brilliant man
저렇게 똑똑한 사람이
likes playing
with toy trains?
왜 장난감 기차를
가지고 노는거야?
Not without cutting
his head open, no.
뚜껑을 열어보지 않으면 몰라
How about making my
eyes like Cleopatra?
클레오파트라처럼
화려하게 해주면 안될까?
Really? For a wedding?
정말? 결혼식에?
Perhaps you're right.
네 말이 맞는거 같다
My cheekbones and
beckoning pelvis
내 아찔한 골반과
아름다운 광대뼈면
already have a certain "hello
sailor" quality to them.
벌써부터 남자들이
껌뻑죽고 난리나지
Ready.
준비됐어
Aw.
So handsome.
Like James Bond.
제임스 본드같아
He's better than James Bond,
because he's tinier.
제임스 본드보다 더 낫지
크기가 더 작으니까
I got you this
to give to me.
이거 나한테 달아줘
Oh, sweetie,
guests don't normally
사실 피로연 손님들은
wear corsages to a wedding.
코르사쥬를 달고오지 않아
That's more of a prom thing.
이건 졸업파티때나 하는거지
I never went to my prom.
난 졸업파티를 못가봤어
My mom paid my cousin
to take me,
엄마가 사촌에게 돈도 줬지만
but he just used the money
to buy drugs.
사촌은 대신 마약을 사고 말았지
Put the corsage on her.
그냥 달아줘
When you're done copping a
feel, that goes on my wrist.
가슴 다 만졌으면 말해
그거 원래 손목에 다는거야
(high-pitched):
All aboard!
탑승완료!
Woo-woo!
(normal voice):
It's official.
I'm an H-O trainiac.
난 HO 기차모형이 좋아
So, dinner
went nice.
저녁은 잘 해결한거 같아
Yeah. Yeah, I guess.
그래, 그런거 같아
Does your mother always
cut your meat for you?
어머니께서 항상
고기를 잘라주시는거야?
Only when it's fatty.
한 입 먹기에 클때만 그래
Well, don't be jealous, babe.
질투하지마 자기야
Someday you'll get to cut it
for me.
나중에 자기가
잘라주면 되잖아
MRS. WOLOWITZ:
Bernadette!
버나뎃!
I found the extra head for the
Waterpik if you want to use it!
치실 필요하면 가져다 쓰거라!
I'm okay, Mrs. Wolowitz.
괜찮아요, 어머니
MRS. WOLOWITZ:
You sure?!
정말 괜찮아?!
I just squirted half a
brisket outta my teeth!
난 이빨에 고기가
한 웅큼이 껴 있던데!
Hey, Ma, how about
a little privacy?!
엄마 프라이버시좀
지켜주면 안돼?!
MRS. WOLOWITZ:
Oh, I know what that means!
아, 그거 하려고!
Hubba-hubba!
Oh, God.
Relax, it'll be fine.
괜찮아 질거야
Okay.
알았어
MRS. WOLOWITZ: Let me know when
you're done canoodling!
큰 일 다 치루면
이야기 해 다오!
Mommy needs a foot rub!
엄마 발마사지좀 해 줘!
♪ ♪
Would you like to dance?
No, thank you.
아니, 괜찮아
I'm really not
much of a dancer.
난 춤을 잘 못춰
You're not exactly
winning any trophies
춤에서든 대화에서든
as a conversationalist, either.
넌 지금 잘 못하고 있어
I'm sorry.
미안해
The bride and groom
seem happy.
신랑신부가 행복해 보여서
AMY:
Why shouldn't they be?
행복한게 당연하지 않아?
They have a feverish night of
오늘 밤이되면 둘은
socially-approved
copulation ahead of them.
사회가 인정한 정사를
즐길수가 있게 되잖아
In some cultures, we'd stand
outside of their bedroom
어떤 나라에서는
하객들이 침실밖에서
cheering as they
achieved orgasm.
부부가 오르가즘에 오르면
같이 환호를 해준대
That sounds like
a late night,
나도 참석하고 싶지만
and I have work in
the morning, so...
내일 일이 있어서...
Leonard, you may
not have noticed,
레너드, 모르는가 본데
but I am being
a delight here.
난 널 기쁘게 하려고
지금 애쓰고 있어
And you're not holding up
your end of the evening.
그런데 너는 별로
시원찮은 반응이다
Oh, sorry. This wedding
just reminds me
미안해. 결혼식에 오니까
of my kinda-sorta girlfriend
9,000 miles away.
이역만리에 떨어져 있는
내 여자친구가 생각나서
I have a kinda-sorta boyfriend
who's playing with a model train
나도 남자친구가
장난감 기차에 미쳐있는데
right now, you don't hear me
bitching about it.
내가 한 번이라도
지랄하는거 들어봤냐
Leonard, a word of advice--
moody self-obsession
레너드, 충고 하나 할게
감상적인 남자가
is only attractive in men
who can play guitar
아름다워 보일때는
그 남자가 키가 크고
and are considerably
taller than you.
기타를 칠 수 있을 때야
I'm not moody.
난 감상적이지 않아
I'm fun.
난 재밌어
You have any evidence
to support that statement?
네 주장을 뒷받침할
어떤 증거라도 있어?
Well, hey, I'm just as
much fun as you are.
나도 너만큼이나 재밌어
Really? Are you willing to draw
a mustache on your finger
정말로? 너라면 손가락에
가짜 수염을 그리고
as a conversational icebreaker?
남을 웃겨줄 수 있어?
I am.
난 할 수 있어
Okay, fine, what
do you suggest?
알았어, 어떻게 할까?
♪ ♪
We just had a lovely meal,
the band... is on fire...
연주도... 끝내주는데
and you're sitting
next to a beautiful woman
네 바로 옆에는
아름다운 여인이
wearing whorish makeup.
섹시한 화장을 하고 왔어
Why don't we head out
on the dance floor
그러니 춤을 추러 나가서
and see if I can sweat
through these dress shields.
내 드레스가 통풍이
잘 되는지 확인해 보자
Once again, I-I'm really
not much of a dancer.
다시 말하는데
난 춤 잘 못춰
Don't worry...
걱정하지마...
I'll lead.
내가 리드할게
("The Chicken Dance" playing)
(imitating lightsaber)
Howard?
(imitates lightsaber
turning off)
Ready for bed?
No. I need to brush my teeth,
but your moth's
아니, 이빨 닦아야 되는데
been in the bathroom
for, like, an hour.
어머니가 화장실을
한시간이나 쓰고계셔
Oh. Yeah, she sometimes has problems
doing her business. Hang on.
아. 가끔씩 엄마가
일을 보는게 힘들어
Ma, give up!
엄마, 포기해요!
Tonight's
not your night!
오늘은 날이 아닌가보지!
MRS. WOLOWITZ: You don't know that!
I just sat down!
아니다 아들아!
곧 나올 것 같아!
WOLOWITZ:
Come on, take a break!
제발요, 그만해요!
Bernadette needs
to brush her teeth!
버나뎃이 이빨을
못 닦고 있잖아요!
MRS. WOLOWITZ: She can come in
and brush her teeth!
들어와서 닦으라 그래라!
I'm not embarrassed!
나는 괜찮아!
Problem solved.
문제 해결
No, it's not.
I'm not going in there.
해결 안됐어
난 못들어가
Oh, come on, honey.
왜그래, 자기야
She's just sitting in there
reading a magazine.
엄마는 그냥 앉아서
잡지만 읽고 계시는거야
You can't see anything.
아무것도 안보여
I go in all the time.
난 항상 들어가거든
(chuckles)
MRS. WOLOWITZ:
Ha! The eagle has landed!
(toilet flushing)
And we have splashdown.
(clears throat)
Wait here, I'm gonna
go light a candle.
And then we make
passionate love.
이제 뜨거운 사랑을 나누자구
There we go, last floor.
다 왔어, 마지막이야
I just can't figure
out what happened.
어떻게 이렇게 된건지
아직도 모르겠어
I put my left leg in,
I took my left leg out,
왼쪽 다리를 안으로 넣고
다시 왼쪽 다리를 빼고
I put my left leg in, and
something just snapped.
다시 왼쪽 다리를 넣었더니
갑자기 다리가 삐끗하더라
The hokey pokey
is a young man's game.
유치원 애들 춤이
좀 어렵긴 해
(chuckles)
I did have a great time.
그래도 재밌었어
Thank you for reminding me
오늘 고마웠어
it's okay to have fun
once in a while.
이렇게 즐기는것도 좋다
You're welcome.
별말씀을
And also for breaking
the head off the ice swan
그리고 백조 얼음
조각을 깨뜨려서
so I could hold it against
my pulled groin.
사타구니 부위를
마사지 하는것도 좋았어
I excel
내가 원래
at spatial reasoning, and I had
a hunch that the graceful slope
공간감각이 뛰어나서
백조 얼음 조각의
of its neck would cradle
your genitals nicely.
목 부분이 네 성기부위에
꼭 맞을거란걸 안거지
Well, okay.
Again, thank you.
아, 그래
어쨋든, 고마워
And again, you're welcome.
그렇다면 또, 별말씀을
Want to come in?
차라도 한 잔 할래?
No, thanks.
I'm gonna head home.
괜찮아, 집에 가야돼
'Kay. Well, good night.
알았어, 잘 자
Good night.
잘자
Ames, hi.
How was the wedding?
에이미, 피로연 재밌었어?
Great. Until I accidentally made
Leonard fall in love with me.
재밌었는데 실수로 레너드가
나한테 반하게 만든 것 같아
Come in, let's talk.
들어와, 말해보자
Do you want a
glass of wine?
와인 한 잔 할래?
Wine is one of the reasons
I'm in this fix.
애초에 와인을 마셔서
이렇게 된거야
That and this dang pelvis.
와인이랑 내 아름다운
골반 때문이지
Okay, I'm sorry,
what exactly happened?
그래, 미안, 어떻게 된건데?
The inevitable--
he was lonely and vulnerable
어쩔 수 없었어, 레너드는
여자친구를 그리워하는데
from missing his girlfriend,
마침 내가 매력적이라
while I was charming,
마음이 약해진거지
supportive and,
let's face it, in this dress,
내가 마음이 따뜻한데다
이런 옷까지 입었으니
the perfect combination
of Madonna and whore.
사랑에 빠지지않고는
못배기게 된거지
Oh, God,
did he make a move on you?
세상에, 뭔 짓이라도 했어?
No, but it's only
a matter of time.
아니, 하지만 시간문제야
How could I have not
seen this coming?
내가 왜 눈치를 못챘을까?
Now I'm gonna have to break
the little sad sack's heart.
이제 어쩔 수 없이
그의 마음을 거절해야지
- Yeah, I'm sure he'll be okay.
- Oh, Penny,
- 괜찮을거야 걱정마
- 오, 페니
much as I would treasure
knowing that the two of us had
같은 남자에게 우리 두 여자가
더럽혀 진 사실에
been defiled by the same man,
너는 좋아라 하겠지만
Leonard just doesn't get
my motor running.
나는 레너드가 전혀 끌리지 않아
So, um, what are
you gonna do?
그럼, 어떻게 할거야?
Do you want me to talk
to Leonard, let him down easy?
내가 얘기좀 해볼까?
조금 진정하게?
No. I'll let him have tonight.
아니. 오늘은 즐기도록 놔둬
Then in the morning,
다음날 아침
I'll send him an e-mail
letting him know
내가 이메일 한 통을 보내
this body is never
gonna be his wonderland.
이 육체는 절대로
넘볼 수 없다 말해주겠어
I mean, frankly, you've got
a better shot than he does.
그래, 사실 걔보다는
너랑 사귀는게 더 낫지
Leonard.
레너드
Check it out.
이것좀 봐
I bought an N-gauge locomotive.
N 게이지 기차를 샀어
Half the size of H-O.
HO의 반만한 크기야
Look, it fits in my mouth.
봐, 내 입에도 들어가
Sounds like you
had a great night.
너도 재밌게 놀았나보네
(muffled):
I did.
맞아
- How was yours?
- Not bad. I had a lot more fun
- 결혼식은 어땠어?
- 괜찮았지, 재밌었고
with Amy than I
thought I would.
에이미가 생각보다 재밌더라고
What exact
do you mean by that?
그게 대체 무슨 얘기야?
Well, it turns out
she really knows
그게, 알고보니 에이미가
how to help a guy loosen up
and have a good time.
남자를 대할 줄 잘 알더라고
Although, truth be told, my
groin's a little worse for wear.
그런데 사실 너무 잘 놀아서
사타구니가 다 아프더라
Ow!
Why did you do that?
To send a message:
she is not for you.
조심하는게 좋을거야
에이미는 네 여자가 아냐
What?
뭐?
Not for you!
네 여자 아냐!
Good morning, handsome.
일어나, 장군님
Morning, Mom.
안녕, 엄마
It's me.
나야
Yes, it is, and you're
so pretty in the morning.
그래, 너 정말 아름답다
Your mom and I
made you breakfast.
어머니랑 같이 아침상 차렸어
(laughs)
Oh, wow.
So you guys are getting along?
Yeah, I guess.
그래, 그런가봐
We're very different
people, Howard,
서로가 너무 달라서
so communication's
a little tricky.
의사소통이 조금 어렵긴 해
MRS. WOLOWITZ:
Does he like the pancakes?!
팬케익 맛있대냐?!
He didn't try them yet!
아직 안 먹었어요!
Is there any butter?
버터는 없어?
- It's butter-flavored syrup.
- Oh.
버터가 들어있는 시럽이야
MRS. WOLOWITZ:
So, what's the word?!
그래, 뭐라디?!
He wants butter!
버터 달래요!
MRS. WOLOWITZ:
It's butter-flavored syrup!
버터가 들어있는 시럽이야!
I just told him that!
그렇게 말했어요!
I don't need any butter.
버터 필요없어
If you want butter,
I'll get you butter.
그렇게 필요하면
내가 가져다 드릴게
Well, I guess
I'll cut these by myself.
이렇게 되면 내가 알아서
잘라 먹어야겠네
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
== translated by 김철영 doatip@gmail.com ==